<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>things to nerd out about</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>iPod, HomePod, iPad, HomePad?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a growing market for voice assistant devices in the past few years. These range from small, $30 circular devices that can plug into other speakers, to fully-integrated speakers, evolving into ones that include screens even.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:12:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /homepad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/homepad</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>SwiftUI - Using Timer for UI refreshes</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;At WWDC this year, one of Apple’s biggest announcements wasn’t a particular feature of the new OSes, but rather a new way to write UIs for your apps using Swift. This new framework, named SwiftUI, uses a declaritive syntax to easily define your UI in far fewer lines of code than before. Along with SwiftUI, Apple announced another framework, Combine, which helps with handling asynchronous events. This post won’t dive into the fundamentals of either of these, there are plenty of others out there already. Instead, this post is intended to work through some challenges I ran into when trying to upgrade my app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/just-timers/id1453573845?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Just Timers&lt;/a&gt;, to use SwiftUI.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 14:16:26 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /swiftui-timer-ui-refresh</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/swiftui-timer-ui-refresh</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>AirPods 2&amp;#58; Electric Boogaloo</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Apple started surprising everyone with a product refresh every day. Starting on Monday, Apple refreshed the iPad Air and Mini, Tuesday saw a refresh of the iMac lineup and finally Wednesday saw the refresh of AirPods. While every product was a bit surprising to see, for most people the AirPods refresh was the most unexpected. There had been rumors of a refresh coming, but they were always pretty vague on details and timing. After much waiting, finally Apple revealed AirPods 2: Electric Boogaloo.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 07:07:36 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /airpods-2-electric-boogaloo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/airpods-2-electric-boogaloo</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Just Timers App Launched</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’ve launched my first iOS app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/just-timers/id1453573845?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Just Timers&lt;/a&gt;. Since iOS can natively only handle a single timer at a time, I’ve frequently found myself frustrated when I need more than one. While the App Store does contain some apps that can create multiple timers, they’re all missing one crucial feature:  Siri control.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 18:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /just-timers-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/just-timers-app</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Belkin Thunderbolt 2 Express HD Dock Review</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is very late to the game, but since there has been a slight resurgence in demand for 2015 Macbook Pro’s of late, I figured it might not hurt to give a short review on this unit. The Belkin Thunderbolt 2 Express HD Dock attempts to be a lot crammed into a relatively small package. At the time of me writing this, it’s been out for a few years and is priced pretty much on par with the other options like it. The nice thing about buying it now, however, is you can pick them up used for a good bit cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 18:49:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /belkin-thunderbolt-2-express-hd-dock</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/belkin-thunderbolt-2-express-hd-dock</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Siri Shortcuts</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;At WWDC this week, Apple announced a huge milestone for Siri: Siri Shortcuts. Back when Apple acquired the company behind Workflow, a powerful automation tool for iOS, there was much speculation on just what would happen. Many feared it would disappear, never to be seen again, but over time we still saw bug fix updates come to the Workflow app. At WWDC they showed off Siri Shortcuts, and an app called Shorcuts that will coincide with this. It is very clear that this Shortcuts app is the result of the Workflow acquisition. The layout is almost identical, but the key difference this time around is that it is much more deeply integrated with iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 17:10:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /siri-shortcuts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/siri-shortcuts</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>WWDC 2018</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s World Wide Developer Conference (WWDC) for 2018 is underway, and to kick things off they had their announcements on Monday, June 4th. While rumors leading up to this event were pretty sparse, the overall tone was that this would be a bug fix year more than a feature-heavy one. Right off the bat they made it clear there would be no hardware announcements, this was all about software. They dove right in to explaining that they were doing a lot to improve performance and stability (Apple’s way of saying “bug fixes”) and even pointed out that these gains alone would make for a great year (roll credits, show is over), but they didn’t stop there. Over the next two hours they went on to explain a plethora of features that were widely unexpected for this year.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 13:49:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /wwdc-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/wwdc-2018</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>AirPort Express as AirPlay Speakers</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks back it was discovered in an iOS beta that &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2018/04/04/airplay-2-airport-express/&quot;&gt;AirPort Express devices were showing up as speakers&lt;/a&gt; in the Home app, implying Apple might be updating these devices to support AirPlay 2. This disappeared in the latest beta, but it has since sparked some interest in using AirPort Expresses for AirPlay speakers, so I thought I’d take some time to write about how I use these devices.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 19:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /airplay-speakers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/airplay-speakers</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Why HomePod isn't ready for my home</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I purchased the HomePod nearly two weeks ago, and today it went back to Apple. I still stand by a lot of what I said in my &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/02/12/e-t-phone-home-pod/&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;. As a speaker, HomePod is fantastic device not just for sound, but for ease of use too. It’s going to be hard to find something that has such omni-directional, quality sound. The size of the HomePod is particularly impressive for what all it accomplishes. Best of all, the complete ease of use (especially compared to the traditional amp and speaker setup that may scare some users away) makes it as painless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /why-i-returned-my-homepod</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/why-i-returned-my-homepod</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>E.T. Phone Home(Pod)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When Apple announced the HomePod and it’s price of $349, I was a little put off, hoping for something cheaper that would allow me to plug into my existing speakers. My interest was more on Siri than the speaker/music aspect of it, but I understand their positioning in such a space, they need to be premium. Pre-orders came and went without me, I decided I wanted to hear some reviews from actual people instead of media outlets before deciding. As expected, early reviews as folks unboxed their units were very positive for the sound, but a bit underwhelmed by Siri. The sound has been the big seller for this device, so of course I would hope it would be good, but as more and more folks compared it to fancier speakers, the more interested I became.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /e-t-phone-home-pod</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/e-t-phone-home-pod</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Alexa’s Skills Pay the Bills?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since Amazon released the Amazon Echo, there has been a growing market for “smart speakers” along with unique features for each. Amazon in particular has grown a very large set of “skills” by allowing anyone to interface with it in some way. While these skills offer some additional functionality, they don’t offer a lot of tangible value for most users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geekwire.com/2016/people-using-amazon-echo-new-study-reveals-surprising-patterns/&quot;&gt;Recent statistics suggest&lt;/a&gt; the majority of users are only using these assistants to set timers, play music and read the news.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 16:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /can-alexas-skills-pay-the-bills</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/can-alexas-skills-pay-the-bills</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Tale of Two (or more) Assistants</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading the comments on just about any post about voice assistants these days will quickly reveal a variety of opinions on each. A lot of people are quick to point to the Google Home or Amazon Echo devices and say how far ahead their assistant devices are compared to something like Apple’s Siri. This is a slightly unfair comparison, since Google Home and Amazon’s Echo (Alexa) assistants are using purpose-built hardware with an array of mics and always-plugged-in power. Line-powered mics will immediately give any assistant a major advantage in that it can be listening much better than on any battery-powered device like a phone or watch. Of course, this really only affects how the device hears a user and interprets their voice. That is only a small (but very important) part of the overall assistant experience.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 18:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /untitled</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/untitled</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>In Defense of Voice Assistants</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time I hear a lot of complaints from people about voice assistants. Whether it be that they just don’t find them useful or they never work right, every case tends to follow some common themes. Now, I don’t mean to pull a Steve Jobs with the old “you’re holding it wrong” type thing, but I would be willing to bet a lot of users simply aren’t using their assistants correctly in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 16:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /in-defense-of-voice-assistants</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/in-defense-of-voice-assistants</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Tech Narratives</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;All tech companies try to preach their narrative for how their hardware/software will change the world–it’s a great idea. The challenge is some tell their story better than others, even when the idea may ultimately be the same. Let’s take an example like Microsoft’s Band. It was marketed as a fitness tracker with tons of useful features, has a curved screen that makes it fairly unobtrusive and even makes it easier to read than something like a traditional watch, but it was still a flop.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 18:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /tech-narratives</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tech-narratives</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Siri Speaker</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Rumors are ramping up lately that Apple will make a Siri speaker soon. This seems reasonable as that space is growing fast and they don’t want to be left behind. Some concerns I’ve read were things like needing a screen for some tasks where these assistants can fall short. What if Apple’s magic up its sleeve is using their Handoff/Continuity features to pass over to your phone when a screen is needed? You make a request, but perhaps it’s a really long article that comes back. Rather than have her read the entire thing, an icon shows up on your phone/iPad/watch or she even vibrates it (based on knowing who asked) so you can read it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /siri-speaker</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/siri-speaker</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Augmented Reality: Audio?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual and Augmented Reality are the buzzwords going around these days. While they aren’t necessarily aiming for the same goals, they aren’t mutually exclusive either. While virtual reality has a lot of potential in certain areas, especially gaming, I’m more excited for the potential offered with augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 21:20:28 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /augmented-reality-audio-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/augmented-reality-audio-2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Apple Watch 2 Years Later</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been two years since the release of the Apple Watch. It’s seen many challenges and changes in a very short time, but looking at the smart watch market, it’s pretty hard to deny it has been a success. Initially, it was met with some struggles both for app developers and users alike. Most third party apps were severely limited by design, causing much frustration, given the expectations people had. Part of this problem was that apps essentially ran on the phone instead of the watch, giving slow performance and unpredictable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 12:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        /a</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/a</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Apple AirPods or: how I learned to stop worrying and love the mob</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple tends to get a lot of press, both positive and negative, surrounding any new products. The biggest headlines tend to be polarizing, between people who are fanatical and unfaltering, to people who have nothing but negative reactions. If you choose sides, which mob are you with?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /apple-airpods-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-mob</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/apple-airpods-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-mob</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Layers of abstraction</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers have had an interesting evolution over the past few decades. Early computers were entirely custom, following very few real standards aside from the load/store model and the likes. Over time, computers began to divide into two fairly distinct designs, CISC (Complex Instruction Set Computer) and RISC (Reduced Instruction Set Computer), with respective pros and cons at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 16:27:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /layers-of-abstraction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/layers-of-abstraction</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Putting the &quot;Air&quot; in AirPods</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was skeptical of AirPods when they first arrived, as so many were. Would they stay in my ears? I had problems with EarPods staying in previously but hoped it was just the weight of the cord, as was often speculated.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 15:38:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /putting-the-air-in-airpods</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/putting-the-air-in-airpods</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Theories on Apple's W1 pairing</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my last post, I’ve been putting a lot more thought into the pairing capabilities of Apple’s new W1 chip. A lot of folks are convinced the W1 itself is where the magic happens. I’m not saying that is impossible, but since Apple insists you must have the latest iOS/macOS and iCloud enabled for the seamless pairing to work, it should be obvious there is a lot more software involved than hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 18:44:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /theories-on-apples-w1-pairing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theories-on-apples-w1-pairing</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Apple's W1 Wireless Chip (and why it may not be so &quot;magical&quot;)</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Apple announced they were dropping the headphone jack from the iPhone 7 to push for a truly wireless future. To further encourage this, they also announced a handful of new wireless headphones between their Beats branding as well as their own Apple branding. Both Beats and Apple (AirPods) headphones would utilize the new, Apple exclusive W1 wireless chip.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 03:08:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        /apples-w1-wireless-chip-and-why-it-may-not-be-so-magical</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/apples-w1-wireless-chip-and-why-it-may-not-be-so-magical</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
